<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">8</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">C</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Cone Tanjur</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>བསྟན་འགྱུར ༼ཅོ་ནེ་པར་ཕུད༽</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Production began several decades after its Kanjur counterpart, with woodblock carving spanning 1753–1772. The project was patronized by Queen and temporary Regent Rinchen Palzom (Rin chen dpal &apos;dzom, 18th cent.) and her grandson Tenpé Sungtsé Tsering (Bstan pa&apos;i srung rtse tshe ring, 1728–1791). The Cone Tanjur used the Derge Tanjur as its primary exemplar, a relationship confirmed by scholarly consensus.

In 1773, the Second Jamyang Zhepa, Könchok Jigme Wangpo (Dkon mchog &apos;jigs med dbang po, 1728–1791) authored the collection&apos;s catalogue &quot;The Rosary of Wish-Fulfilling Gems: A Detailed Catalogue of the Precious Teaching&apos;s Word&quot; (Bstan bcos &apos;gyur ro cog gi dkar chag yid bzhin nor bu&apos;i phreng ba).

The collection comprises either 208 volumes with 65,425 folios according to its catalogue, or 209 volumes as reported by J.F. Rock. By the mid-20th century, complete copies were preserved at the Library of Congress, Wu-fai-shan monastery, and Yonghe Temple (雍和宮) in Peking. The 1929 destruction of the original woodblocks has made surviving complete copies of the Cone canon particularly valuable.</abstract>
  <genre>Tanjur</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1772</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Coné Ganden Shedrub Ling</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>34.59525,103.50381</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="placeref" authority="BDRC">G435</identifier>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/G435</url>
  </location>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">true</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">true</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">10</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW1GS66030</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW1GS66030</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">BDRC</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">0</note>
      <form type="medium">Print</form>
      <scriptTerm type="text">Uchen</scriptTerm>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <physicalDescription>
      <extent>209</extent>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
