<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">37</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">Go</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Gondhla Collection</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>གོན་དྷོ་ལར་བཞུགས་པའི་དཔེ་རྙིང་ཕྱོགས་བསྒྲིགས།</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>The Gondhla Canonical Collection is a valuable assemblage of Tibetan Buddhist manuscripts from Gondhla, Lahaul, Himachal Pradesh, India. Stored in the Thakur&apos;s castle tower, it is not a Kanjur in the strict sense of a standardized, canonical compilation. Helmut Tauscher classifies it as a proto-Kanjur—an early attempt to bring together the &quot;words of the Buddha&quot; before canonical structures emerged in the early 14th century.

The collection’s precise origins remain debated. Its illuminated art suggests a possible 11th–12th century provenance, but palaeographic and orthographic evidence points more convincingly to the late 13th or early 14th century. The manuscripts were not produced as a single set; some are slightly younger than others.

Local traditions claim the Gondhla collection is half of a set, with the other containing missing Prajñāpāramitā and tantric texts at Phukthar monastery in Zanskar. However, research at Phukthar revealed this is unsubstantiated, as the manuscripts there do not complete the Gondhla group. It is likely the Gondhla proto-Kanjur never contained a full canonical set. 

The collection contains 35 partially illuminated volumes; an additional collection is preserved by by Mr. Ramesh Thakur, Gondhala village, Lahaul, in 47 volumes. 

The arrangement of texts is often disordered; passages from different texts interrupt each other, suggesting scribes copied from exemplars with already-mixed folios.

Physically, the manuscripts typify early Western Tibetan book production: thick, coarse, brownish-beige paper, with folio dimensions around 67–69 x 19–21 cm. The script is dbu can, preserving many archaic orthographic forms inconsistently, helping date the manuscripts and link them to those from Tabo. The collection is more closely related to the Them spangs ma group of Kanjurs (e.g., Stog Palace Kanjur) than to the Tshal pa lineage (e.g., Derge, Peking editions).

The Gondhla Kanjur is one of the most complete proto-Kanjur collections extant, providing key evidence for the Tibetan canon’s development before the Old Narthang Kanjur’s (est. ca. 1330) standardization. Its composition and omissions illuminate which texts were circulating in Western Tibet and how scripture was organized in that period.</abstract>
  <genre>Canonical Collection</genre>
  <classification>Them spangs ma</classification>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>11th–14th cent.</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Gondhla</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>32.509444,77.019444</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="placeref" authority="BDRC">G4342</identifier>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/G4342</url>
  </location>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">true</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">true</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">31</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW2KG5016</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW2KG5016</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="imagesby">BDRC</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">0</note>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <physicalDescription>
      <extent>47</extent>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">32</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW1PD128753</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW1PD128753</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">TMPV</note>
      <note type="imagesby">BDRC</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">0</note>
      <note type="integratedrkts">0</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">0</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <physicalDescription>
      <extent>36</extent>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
