<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">42</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">Gtb</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Nyingma Gyübum (Tsamdrak)</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>མཚམས་བྲག་དགོན་དུ་རྙིང་མ་རྒྱུད་འབུམ།</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>The Tsamdrak Nyingma Gyübum is a 46-volume illuminated manuscript preserved at Tsamdrak monastery (Mtshams brag dgon pa) in Thimphu district, Bhutan. It is widely recognized as one of the most complete and influential witnesses to the Bhutanese transmission of the Nyingma tantric canon.

The production of the Tsamdrak edition is traditionally credited to Tsamdrak Trülku Ngawang Drukpa (Mtshams brag sprul sku Ngag dbang ’brug pa, 1682–1748), a disciple of Tenzin Legpé Döndrup (Bstan ’dzin legs pa’i don grub) of nearby Gangtey monastery. The likely date of production is between 1726 and 1748. The collection is a part of the Central Bhutanese group of Nyingma Gyübum transmissions, which also includes key sets from Gangtey and Sangyé Ling.

The Tsamdrak Nyingma Gyübum is noted for its exceptional quality, scribal accuracy, and completeness, comprising 46 substantial volumes and about 1,000 texts. The codicological features include illuminated title folios, gold ink, and meticulous pagination, with consistent volume and folio numbering, double headmarks (yig mgo), and precise layout reflecting the high caliber of the scriptorium.

Its entire textual structure and doxographical sequence precisely match the Gangtey (B) set—both collections are considered “identical twins” (Mayer &amp; Cantwell 2006). The corpus is strictly limited to the three highest classes of Vajrayāna tantras: Mahāyoga, Anuyoga, and Atiyoga, as categorized in the Nyingma tradition. Many additional treasure (gter ma) texts, such as those by Dorjé Lingpa (Rdo rje gling pa, 1346–1405) and from the Northern Treasure (Byang gter) tradition, are present, while notable omissions and inclusions (compared to other editions) reflect the unique editorial history of this version.

Textual criticism shows Tsamdrak and Gangtey (B) to share a common, now-lost ancestor, not standing in a simple parent-child relationship. Both reflect the Bhutanese transmission line, distinct from the Southern Central and Eastern Tibetan recensions. The Bhutanese lines themselves were largely established through the efforts of Lhomön Kathokpa master Sönam Gyaltsen (Lho mon Kaḥ thog pa Bsod nams rgyal mtshan, 1466–1540), Tsültrim Dorjé (Pad gling gsung sprul III Tshul khrims rdo rje, 1598–1669), and subsequent Nyingma hierarchs, who ensured the survival of the corpus through careful copying and transmission during periods of sectarian strife and external threats.

After the widespread destruction of religious libraries during the 20th century, the Tsamdrak edition was published by photo-offset lithography in Delhi (1981) with sponsorship from Dilgo Khyentse Rinpoche, the National Library of Bhutan, and with scholarly guidance from Lopön Pemala. This edition, since reproduced on microfiche, in Western-style bindings, in Chengdu, and digitally by the TBRC and the Tibetan and Himalayan Library, was a milestone for securing the preservation and international accessibility of the Nyingma canon at a time when it faced potential loss.

The entire Tsamdrak edition has now been digitized and catalogued as part of the Endangered Archives Programme’s EAP310-4-1 project (https://eap.bl.uk/collection/EAP310-4-1).</abstract>
  <genre>Old Tantra</genre>
  <classification>Bhutanese (NGB)</classification>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1726–1728</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Tsamdrak Monastery</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>27.251120638023302,89.54917742883593</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="placeref" authority="BDRC">G382</identifier>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/G382</url>
  </location>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">false</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">true</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">36</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW21521</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW21521</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">BDRC</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">7</note>
      <form type="medium">Manuscript</form>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">94</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MWEAP310-4-1</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MWEAP310-4-1</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">EAP</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">7</note>
      <form type="medium">Manuscript</form>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">0</note>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
