<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">53</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">L</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>London Kanjur</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>ཤེལ་དཀར་བཀའ་འགྱུར།</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>The London Kanjur—sometimes called the Shel dkar Manuscript Kanjur—is a principal manuscript witness for the Thempangma lineage of the Tibetan Kanjur. It is preserved at the British Library (Or. 6724) and derives its alternative name from its origins at Shelkar Chödé (Shel dkar Chos sde), a Gelukpa monastery in Latö (La stod), Southern Tibet.

Copied directly from the Shelkar Chödé master manuscript, its production began in the early 18th century and was completed in 1712 (Water-Dragon year, chu ‘brug). The project was a major collaborative effort, involving thirty calligraphers from Némo (sne mo), editorial oversight by ten Shelkar monks, and sponsorship from lay donors including Rdo legs rnam rgyal, with notable support from female patrons Byams pa dpal mo (nun) and Bstan ‘dzin dpal mo. The completed set was consecrated by Shelkar monks, and associated artworks were consecrated by the Fifth Panchen Lama, Lobsang Yeshe (Blo bzang ye shes, 1663–1737), situating the project firmly in this historical period.

The manuscript brought to the West by L. A. Waddell during the British expedition of 1903–1904, now housed in London, at the British Library, preserved on microfilm. Several volumes are also held by the Bodleian Libraries, Oxford.

The London Kanjur’s production history is richly documented in three poetic catalogues, which detail its patrons and scribe team and celebrate the spiritual merit of the project. Its Thempangma affiliations, established by Helmut Eimer and confirmed by Peter Skilling, correct prior misattributions to the Tshalpa lineage.

While largely faithful to its lineage, the London Manuscript Kanjur shows occasional textual influences from Western Tibetan sources, hinting at editorial engagement with readings beyond strict Thempangma tradition. Its catalogues, rather than being mere indexes, provide unique literary background on the collection’s creation.</abstract>
  <genre>Kanjur</genre>
  <classification>Thempangma</classification>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1712</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Shelkar Chödé</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>28.133056,87.116667</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="placeref" authority="BDRC">G221</identifier>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/G221</url>
  </location>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">true</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">true</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">47</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW3CN981</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW3CN981</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">TMPV</note>
      <note type="imagesby">BDRC</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">8</note>
      <form type="medium">Manuscript</form>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
