<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">84</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">Td</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Thadrak Kanjur</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>ཐ་བྲག་བཀའ་འགྱུར།</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>The Thadrak Kanjur is a manuscript collection held at Thadrak Temple, located a few hours&apos; climb from Thimphu, Bhutan. The collection is part of the broader archival initiative documented by the Endangered Archives Programme (https://eap.bl.uk/project/EAP310). Thadrak, along with the temple libraries of Tshamdrak and Neyphug, preserves ancient Buddhist texts and other works that have remained largely unknown and often inaccessible to scholars.

The Thadrak Kanjur comprises 109 volumes of manuscripts in loose-leaf poti format, written in Tibetan dbu can script. The set includes a diverse array of canonical genres:

- 20 volumes of rGyud &apos;bum (Tantras)
- 3 volumes of Nyingma rGyud &apos;bum (Nyingma Tantras)
- 1 volume of Dus &apos;khor (Kālacakra)
- 2 volumes of Shri dri med &apos;od
- 32 volumes of mDo sde (Sūtras)
- 13 volumes of &apos;Dul ba (Vinaya)
- 16 volumes of Sher phyin (Prajñāpāramitā)
- 6 volumes of dKon brtsegs (Ratnakūṭa)
- 6 volumes of Phal chen (Avataṃsaka)
- 4 volumes of Myang &apos;das (Parinirvāṇa)  

Although specific historical details on the origin and development of Thadrak Temple are sparse, the site was once a thriving religious centre and is associated with a Vajrakīla tradition known as Phur pa mtha&apos; brag ma. The manuscript collection itself represents a highly ecumenical corpus, with approximately seventy titles in total, including not only canonical texts but also works on philosophy, language, meditation, ritual, and more than twenty-six biographical and historical treatises—many of them rare or little-known in Buddhist scholarship.

The majority of the manuscripts are dated between the 18th and early 20th centuries, though some titles are likely several hundred years older, with a few plausibly from as early as the 14th or 15th century.</abstract>
  <genre>Kanjur</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>18th cent.</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Thadrak Monastery</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>27.47298875804195,89.67499737729304</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">false</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">true</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">68</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MWEAP310-1-1</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MWEAP310-1-1</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="digitizedby">EAP</note>
      <note type="numberoflines">0</note>
      <form type="medium">Manuscript</form>
      <note type="integratedrkts">1</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
