<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
  <identifier type="local">93</identifier>
  <identifier type="sigla">V</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Ulaanbaatar Kanjur</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative" lang="tib">
    <title>བཀའ་འགྱུར ༼རྒྱལ་རྩེ་ཐེམ་སྤང་མ༽</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>The Ulaanbaatar Thempangma Kanjur is a complete and well-preserved Tibetan manuscript collection held at the National Library of Mongolia in Ulaanbaatar. Recognized as a key witness to the Thempangma (them spangs ma) transmission lineage of the Tibetan Buddhist canon, it is written on thick glossy Tibetan paper in black ink, each folio measuring approximately 70.5 cm x 25 cm with a print area of 14.5 cm x 59 cm arranged in eight lines per page. Two distinctive horizontal circles are set in the middle of each page.

This manuscript, most commonly called the Ulaanbaatar Thempangma Kanjur to distinguish it from other Kanjurs in the city&apos;s archives. The collection comprises 114 volumes, although, in the current digital edition, volumes 40, 41, and 56 are missing. The set was brought to Mongolia around 1671 as a gift to the first Jetsun Dampa Khutuktu, Lobsang Tenpé Gyaltsen (Blo bzang bstan pa&apos;i rgyal mtshan, 1635–1723), from the 5th Dalai Lama. It is probable that its original catalogue volume was already missing at that time, and a new handwritten catalogue was later compiled for this collection.

This Kanjur is one of the five principal manuscript collections in the Thempangma group, stemming from a foundational manuscript compiled in Gyantse (rgyal rtse) around 1431. Its textual transmission is noteworthy for relying on handwritten copies rather than woodblock prints, and the Ulaanbaatar Thempangma Kanjur is valued for its close preservation of the original tradition.

The arrangement and titles of the texts in this edition show some variation from the other major Thempangma Kanjur editions—such as the Stog Palace, Shelkar (London), and Tokyo (Toyo Bunko) manuscripts. The present manuscript contains 833 titles, one fewer than found in the hand-list of Géza Bethlenfalvy, which was compiled from the Register (thob yig) of Dzaya Paṇḍita (Dz+ya paNDita, 1642–1708) as well as an earlier catalogue. Notably, several titles appear in these lists but are not found in the physical manuscript itself, and missing volumes are listed in accordance with consecutive numbers based on the Register of Dzaya Paṇḍita.

Since 2007, the digitization of the Thempangma manuscript (rgyal rtse’i them spangs ma) has been a collaborative project led by the National Library of Mongolia, the Asian Classics Input Project (ACIP), and the Yuishoji Buddhist Cultural Exchange Research Institute (YBCERI), Tokyo. The process involved meticulous digital scanning, image processing, and verification, with the results published in a set of seven DVDs by the Digital Preservation Society, Tokyo. The digitization concluded in 2016, and the complete collection (aside from the three missing volumes, as described above) is now accessible internationally. An incomplete catalogue—compiled later than the manuscript itself—is included with the digital edition.</abstract>
  <genre>Kanjur</genre>
  <classification>Them spangs ma</classification>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1671</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Lhasa?</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>29.657917,91.117167</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="placeref" authority="BDRC">G1PD129184</identifier>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/G1PD129184</url>
  </location>
  <note type="handlist" displayLabel="Handlist Available">true</note>
  <note type="images" displayLabel="Images Available">false</note>
  <note type="text" displayLabel="Text Available">false</note>
  <relatedItem type="constituent">
    <identifier type="local">74</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>MW1KG14700</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://purl.bdrc.io/resource/MW1KG14700</url>
    </location>
    <physicalDescription>
      <note type="numberoflines">0</note>
      <form type="medium">Manuscript</form>
      <scriptTerm type="text">Uchen</scriptTerm>
      <note type="integratedrkts">0</note>
      <note type="isreferenceset">1</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <physicalDescription>
      <extent>0</extent>
    </physicalDescription>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
